A Guide to the Food and Agricultural Education Information System Reports, [1981]-2001
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Food and Agricultural Education Information System Reports [1981]-2001
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2008-094
2 containers; 1.0 cu. ft.
Statistical data compiled by the Food and Agricultural Education Information System regarding college enrollment and degrees in such majors as Agriculture, Family and Consumer Science, Forestry, Home Economics, and Renewable Natural Resources.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Food and Agricultural Education Information System Reports were donated to Special Collections in 2008.
Historical Information
The Food and Agricultural Education Information System (FAEIS) is a program which compiles nationwide higher education data for the agricultural, food, human, life, natural resource, and veterinary sciences. These data include student enrollment, degrees awarded and placement at all degree levels and faculty salaries by rank and discipline. FAEIS was developed by the U.S. Department of Agriculture in 1983 and originally managed by Texas A & M University. Virginia Tech began managing FAEIS in 2002.
Scope and Content
This collection contains a set of reports compiled by the Food and Agricultural Education Information System. The reports consist of compiled data on higher education in the fields of agricultural, food, human, life, natural resource, and veterinary sciences. Included are such statistics as student enrollment, degrees awarded and placement at all degree levels as well as faculty salaries by rank and discipline. Dates covered by these reports span from 1971 to 1999.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by field of study, then by report type, then chronologically.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Food Technology and Production; History of Food and Drink; Science and Technology
Contents List
- Agriculture and Natural Resources
  - Enrollment (Fall 1991) Feb 1992 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Enrollment (Fall 1992) Jun 1993 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Agriculture, Renewable Resources, and Forestry
  - Degrees Awarded and Placement (1997/98) Jul 1999 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Degrees Awarded and Placement (1998/99) Nov 2000 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Enrollment (Fall 1993) Oct 1994 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Enrollment (Fall 1995) May 1996 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Enrollment (Fall 1996) Aug 1997 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Enrollment (Fall 1997) Nov 1998 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Enrollment (Fall 1998) Jul 1999 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Enrollment (Fall 1999) Jun 2000 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Agriculture, Natural Resources, Forestry, Veterinary Medicine and Allied Fields
  - Longitudinal Summary of U.S. Graduates by Degree Level and Type of Institution (1971/72-1980/81) [1983?] (Box-folder 2-1)
  - Longitudinal Summary of U.S. Graduates with Scientific/Professional Expertise [1997?] (Box-folder 2-2)
- Family Science and Consumer Sciences
  - Degrees Awarded (Academic Year 1997/1998) May 1999 (Box-folder 2-3)
  - Degrees Awarded (Academic Year 1999/2000) Jul 2001 (Box-folder 2-4)
  - Enrollment (Fall 1995) Sep 1996 (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Enrollment (Fall 1997) Aug 1998 (Box-folder 2-6)
  - Enrollment (Fall 1999) Mar 2000 (Box-folder 2-7)
- Home Economics
  - Enrollment (Fall 1990) Nov 1991 (Box-folder 2-8)
  - Enrollment and New Faculty Profiles (1991/92) Nov 1991 (Box-folder 2-9)
  - Enrollment (Fall 1993) Jul 1994 (Box-folder 2-10)
  - Longitudinal Summary of U. S. Graduates (1982/83-1996/97) [1997?] (Box-folder 2-11)